Guide to the Liederkranz Collection ca. 1847-1987 MSS.130
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series IV: Printed Sheet Music Collection, 63573
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Am Niagara! Uniform Title: Am Niagara! Publisher information: New York: Carl Fischer Plate Number: 4256-5 1/2, undated; 31142040613476; 63654 (Box 149, Folder 2138)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Auf dem Alpensee Uniform Title: Auf dem Alpensee Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Kistner (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 8851 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613443; 63653 (Box 152, Folder 2298)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Aventiure Uniform Title: Aventiure Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Carl Klinner (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: C.K. 2102 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613468; 63652 (Box 150, Folder 2188)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Bei Sedan. 1870 Uniform Title: Bei Sedan. 1870, undated; 31142040613427; 63651 (Box 154, Folder 2389)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Bonifacius Uniform Title: Bonifacius Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): F. E. C. Leuckart Plate Number: F. E. C. L. 5657 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040612643; 63650 (Box 79, Folder 1017)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Columbus Uniform Title: Columbus (Germany) (E. Jul. Pickenhahn, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 7851, undated; 31142040613542; 63649 (Box 142, Folder 1979)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Columbus Uniform Title: Columbus (Germany) (E. Jul. Pickenhahn, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 7852, undated; 31142040613542; 63648 (Box 142, Folder 1980)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Das Fest der Rebenbluthe Uniform Title: Fest der Rebenbluthe Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (E. Jul. Pickenhahn [printer]) Plate Number: 6506, undated; 31142040613393; 63647 (Box 157, Folder 2494)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Das Fest der Rebenbluthe Uniform Title: Fest der Rebenbluthe Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (E. Jul. Pickenhahn [printer]) Plate Number: 6508, undated; 31142040613393; 63646 (Box 157, Folder 2495)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Das Fest der Rebenbluthe Uniform Title: Fest der Rebenbluthe Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (E. Jul. Pickenhahn, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 6504, undated; 31142040613096; 63645 (Box 124, Folder 1798)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Das Fest der Rebenbluthe Uniform Title: Fest der Rebenbluthe Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (E. Jul. Pickenhahn, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 6505, undated; 31142040613096; 63644 (Box 124, Folder 1799)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Das Fest der Rebenbluthe Uniform Title: Fest der Rebenbluthe Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (E. Jul. Pickenhahn, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 6506, undated; 31142040613096; 63643 (Box 124, Folder 1800)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Das Glockenlied von Speyer Uniform Title: Glockenlied von Speyer Publisher information: Heidelberg (Germany): Karl Hochstein (Universitatsdruckerei, H. Sturz A. G., Wurzburg [printer]) Plate Number: H.2744 H., undated; 31142040612833; 63642 (Box 98, Folder 1235)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Das holzerne Schwert Uniform Title: Holzerne Schwert Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Breitkopf and Härtel Plate Number: Orch.B.1267/68., undated; 31142040613179; 63641 (Box 132, Folder 1884)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Der Liebsten Namen Uniform Title: Liebsten Namen Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Kistner (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 8850 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613476; 63640 (Box 149, Folder 2159)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Der Todesritt von Mars la Tour Uniform Title: Todesritt von Mars la Tour Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Robert Forberg (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 4892 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613245; 63639 (Box 172, Folder 3127)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Die Freiheit Uniform Title: Freiheit Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): F. E. C. Leuckart (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: F. E. C. L. 6558, undated; 31142040613237; 63638 (Box 173, Folder 3168)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Die Wacht um Mitternacht Uniform Title: Wacht um Mitternacht Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Kistner (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 8848 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613484; 63637 (Box 148, Folder 2132)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Entweder-oder! Uniform Title: Entweder-oder! Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Kistner (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 6771 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613393; 63636 (Box 157, Folder 2475)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Heerschau Uniform Title: Heerschau Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Gebruder Hug and Co. Plate Number: G. H. 3002 a/d., undated; 31142040612650; 63635 (Box 80, Folder 1023)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Heerschau Uniform Title: Heerschau Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Gebruder Hug and Co. Plate Number: G. H. 3002a. Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040612692; 63634 (Box 84, Folder 1065)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Heerschau Uniform Title: Heerschau Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Gebruder Hug and Co. Plate Number: G. H. 3002c. Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040612692; 63633 (Box 84, Folder 1064)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Hymnus der Liebe Uniform Title: Hymnus der Liebe, undated; 31142040613567; 63632 (Box 140, Folder 1953)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Hymnus der Liebe Uniform Title: Hymnus der Liebe Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 9187 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613567; 63631 (Box 140, Folder 1952)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Hymnus der Liebe Uniform Title: Hymnus der Liebe Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 9189 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613435; 63630 (Box 153, Folder 2331)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: In der Fremde Uniform Title: In der Fremde, undated; 31142040613211; 63629 (Box 175, Folder 3276)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: In der Fremde Uniform Title: In der Fremde Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Kistner Plate Number: 7302, undated; 31142040613336; 63628 (Box 163, Folder 2716)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Indianischer Liebesgesang Uniform Title: Indianischer Liebesgesang Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 9607 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613575; 63627 (Box 139, Folder 1949)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Indianischer Liebesgesang Uniform Title: Indianischer Liebesgesang Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 9608 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613575; 63626 (Box 139, Folder 1950)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Indianischer Liebesgesang Uniform Title: Indianischer Liebesgesang Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 9609 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613575; 63625 (Box 139, Folder 1951)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Jung Siegfried Uniform Title: Jung Siegfried Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (E. Jul. Pickenhahn [printer]) Plate Number: 6736, undated; 31142040612676; 63624 (Box 82, Folder 1043)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Jung Siegfried Uniform Title: Jung Siegfried Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (E. Jul. Pickenhahn [printer]) Plate Number: 6737, undated; 31142040612676; 63623 (Box 82, Folder 1044)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Jung Siegfried Uniform Title: Jung Siegfried Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (E. Jul. Pickenhahn [printer]) Plate Number: 6738, undated; 31142040612676; 63622 (Box 82, Folder 1042)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Jung Siegfried Uniform Title: Jung Siegfried Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (E. Jul. Pickenhahn [printer]) Plate Number: 6739, undated; 31142040613260; 63621 (Box 170, Folder 2999)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Konig Sigurd Ring's Brautfahrt Uniform Title: Konig Sigurd Ring's Brautfahrt Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): F. E. C. Leuckart (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: F. E. C. L. 4890 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613104; 63620 (Box 125, Folder 1812)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Konig Sigurd Ring's Brautfahrt Uniform Title: Konig Sigurd Ring's Brautfahrt Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): F. E. C. Leuckart (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: F. E. C. L. 4893 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613104; 63619 (Box 125, Folder 1813)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Lied des Schmied's Uniform Title: Rattenfanger von Hameln. Lied des Schmied's Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Kistner Plate Number: 4807, undated; 31142040613328; 63618 (Box 164, Folder 2771)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Meine Gottin Uniform Title: Meine Gottin Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Breitkopf and Härtel, undated; 31142040613302; 63617 (Box 166, Folder 2835)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: O Heimath Uniform Title: O Heimath Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Kistner (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 8847 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613286; 63616 (Box 168, Folder 2918)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Ode to Music Uniform Title: Musik Publisher information: New York: G. Schirmer Plate Number: 13188, undated; 31142040613229; 63615 (Box 174, Folder 3203)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Preis der deutschen Musik Uniform Title: Preis der deutschen Musik Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 9519 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613286; 63614 (Box 168, Folder 2941)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Rosenschneien Uniform Title: Rosenschneien Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): F. E. C. Leuckart Plate Number: F. E. C. L. 6568, undated; 31142040613278; 63613 (Box 169, Folder 2978)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Schlummerlied Uniform Title: Schlummerlied Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Robert Forberg (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 4899 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613245; 63612 (Box 172, Folder 3118)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Talismane Uniform Title: Talismane Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 15372 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613583; 63611 (Box 138, Folder 1933)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Talismane Uniform Title: Talismane Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 15374 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613583; 63610 (Box 138, Folder 1931)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Talismane Uniform Title: Talismane Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): C. F. W. Siegel's Musikalienhandlung (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 15375. Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613583; 63609 (Box 138, Folder 1932)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Um und um, frumm und krumm Uniform Title: Um und um, frumm und krumm Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Kistner Plate Number: 6772, undated; 31142040613245; 63608 (Box 172, Folder 3136)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Unstate Liebe Uniform Title: Unstate Liebe Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Kistner (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 8849 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613245; 63607 (Box 172, Folder 3139)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Wanderer's Nachtlied Uniform Title: Wanderer's Nachtlied Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Kistner (C. G. Röder, Leipzig [printer]) Plate Number: 8846 Engraver: C. G. Röder, Leipzig, undated; 31142040613427; 63606 (Box 154, Folder 2371)
  - Composer: Zollner, Heinrich Title: Young Harry of Steier Uniform Title: Heini von Steier Publisher information: Milwaukee: Wm. Rohlfing and Sons Plate Number: 545, undated; 31142040613492; 63605 (Box 147, Folder 2117)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: America the Beautiful Uniform Title: America the Beautiful, undated; 31142040612924; 63604 (Box 107, Folder 1527)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Children's Song Book Uniform Title: Children's Song Book Publisher information: New York: Edward Schuberth and Co., undated; 31142040613211; 63603 (Box 175, Folder 3299)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Chor der Druiden und des Heidenvolks Uniform Title: Chor der Druiden und des Heidenvolks Plate Number: 1401, undated; 31142040613005; 63602 (Box 115, Folder 1649)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Das froehliche Standchen Uniform Title: Froehliche Standchen, undated; 31142040613344; 63601 (Box 162, Folder 2680)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Das treue deutsche Herz Uniform Title: Treue deutsche Herz, undated; 31142040612957; 63600 (Box 110, Folder 1579)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Des Abends Uniform Title: Des Abends, undated; 31142040613419; 63599 (Box 155, Folder 2416)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Die Dorfmusik Uniform Title: Dorfmusik, undated; 31142040612650; 63598 (Box 80, Folder 1026)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Die Lust'ge Band Uniform Title: Lust'ge Band, undated, undated; 31142040613310; 63597 (Box 165, Folder 2797)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Ecce quam bonum Uniform Title: Ecce quam bonum Publisher information: New York: Deutscher Liederkranz, undated; 31142040612981; 63596 (Box 113, Folder 1614)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Einer von unsere Leut. Selections Uniform Title: Einer von unsere Leut. Selections, undated; 31142040613013; 63595 (Box 116, Folder 1651)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Five Favorite Yule-Tide Songs Uniform Title: Five Favorite Yule-Tide Songs Publisher information: New York: Carl Fischer Plate Number: 15068-17 1/2, undated; 31142040613120; 63594 (Box 127, Folder 1854)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Grablied Uniform Title: Grablied, undated; 31142040613369; 63593 (Box 160, Folder 2601)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Hinaus auf die Sie! Uniform Title: Hinaus auf die Sie!, undated; 31142040613344; 63592 (Box 162, Folder 2667)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Hoch! Uniform Title: Hoch!, undated; 31142040613336; 63591 (Box 163, Folder 2713)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Horch, was kommt Uniform Title: Horch, was kommt, undated; 31142040613351; 63590 (Box 161, Folder 2654)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: L. K. Sangerspruch Uniform Title: L. K. Sangerspruch, undated; 31142040613260; 63589 (Box 170, Folder 3018)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Look for the silver lining Uniform Title: Look for the silver lining, undated; 31142040613310; 63588 (Box 165, Folder 2810)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: March Along Uniform Title: March Along, undated; 31142040613294; 63587 (Box 167, Folder 2869)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Nun danket all Gott; Eine feste Burg Uniform Title: Nun danket alle Gott; Ein feste Burg Publisher information: New York: G. Schirmer Plate Number: 1275, undated; 31142040613401; 63586 (Box 156, Folder 2469)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: O du frohliche Uniform Title: O du frohliche, undated; 31142040613120; 63585 (Box 127, Folder 1835)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: O komm, mein Kind, zum Wald hinein! Uniform Title: O komm, mein Kind, zum Wald hinein! Publisher information: Leipzig (Germany): Breitkopf and Härtel Plate Number: Ch.B.249., undated; 31142040613286; 63584 (Box 168, Folder 2920)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: O Tannenbaum Uniform Title: O Tannenbaum, undated; 31142040613005; 63583 (Box 115, Folder 1646)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Puer natus Uniform Title: Puer natus Publisher information: New York Engraver: Otto Lobner, undated; 31142040613450; 63582 (Box 151, Folder 2236)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Regenhusch Uniform Title: Regenhusch, undated; 31142040613120; 63581 (Box 127, Folder 1861)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Sanctus Uniform Title: Sanctus, undated; 31142040613005; 63580 (Box 115, Folder 1642)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Tell me where is Fancy bred? Uniform Title: Tell me where is Fancy bred?, undated; 31142040613344; 63579 (Box 162, Folder 2695)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: The star spangled banner Uniform Title: Star spangled banner, undated; 31142040613468; 63578 (Box 150, Folder 2184)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Veteranen Fest Uniform Title: Veteranen Fest, undated; 31142040612650; 63577 (Box 80, Folder 1027)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Waldabendschein Uniform Title: Waldabendschein Publisher information: New York, undated; 31142040613021; 63576 (Box 117, Folder 1677)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Wehmuts Lieder Uniform Title: Wehmuts Lieder, undated; 31142040612650; 63575 (Box 80, Folder 1029)
  - Composer: [n/a] Title: Weihnachtsglocken Uniform Title: Weihnachtsglocken, undated; 31142040613005; 63574 (Box 115, Folder 1647)
- Oversize Series IC: Music, Choral, 63570
  - "Deutsche Volkslieder," orchestrated by Papageno for the 1963 Charity Concert, orchestra and chorus, score, manuscript, 63572 (Box IC.1, Folder 94A)
  - Liszt, Franz, "Missa Solemnis," score, probably 1st ed., 1859, 63571 (Box IC.2, Folder 53A)
- Oversize Series IIA: Liederkranz Library Documents / Materials, 63567
  - Liederkranz Music Library's Card Catalog, undated; 63569 (Box IIA.3, Folder 195A)
  - "Season of 1924-1925, Seating of Orchestra, Rehearsal Room, Scale ½" = 1'0"," seating map, two copies, found folded in large library ledger (folder 203), 1924-09-24; 63568 (Folder 3 Left)